Mohak Tamhane

Princeton, NJ 08540 | Phone: <u>+1 (609) 619-2964</u> | Email: <u>tamhane.mohak@gmail.com</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/mohak92</u> | LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/mohakt</u> | Portfolio: <u>mohaktamhane.com</u>

Summary

Full Stack Application Developer with extensive experience writing clean and efficient code. Masters in Computer Science and dedication to continuous learning. Ability to transform user requirements to design and architect solutions developing highly scalable production level applications. Strong communication and leadership skills and attention to detail make me a strong asset to any software development engineering and front-end engineering team.

Skills

- Front End: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6, jQuery, Handlebars, React, Redux, React-Hooks, Vue.js
- Back End: Node.js, Express.js, Java
- Database: Oracle, MySQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Firebase
- Deployment: AWS, Heroku, Git, SVN

Experience

Software Development Engineer Tata Consultancy Services

(Jul 2018 – Present) Edison, NJ

Project: AIG General Insurance - Evergreen workflow automated notification and scanning

- Developed an automation tool for the Evergreen app hardening team to send automatic notification to application owners and portfolio owner, and run automated app scan and dynamic scan.
- Secured application from critical flaws that would allow SQL injections and Cross Site Scripting. Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Data, React, MongoDB, Veracode APIs, REST APIs, Git

Project: CVS Health - Opioid Dosing Module, Refill at Pickup

Woonsocket, RI

- Worked on development of multiple releases of Rx-Connect which is a large-scale software, with practical capabilities and features designed to streamline pharmacy operations, reduce risks and ensure patient safety.
- Participated in daily scrum meetings and tech discussions to solve problem and provide solutions to stakeholders.
- Optimized prescription refill, implemented RESTful services to get data for refill of prescription from POS.
- Analyzed requirements and implemented code to transfer refill-prescriptions from one pharmacy to another.
- Implemented functionality from scratch to help pharmacist decide whether to dispense opioids to patient without putting the patient at risk.
- Deployed and tested applications in dev and test environment using QuickBuild. Technologies: Java 8 J2EE, Spring Framework, RESTful Webservices, Oracle SQL, WebLogic, SVN

Junior Software Associate Synechron

(Jan 2017 - June 2017) New York, NY

• Developed and maintained internal HRMS (Human Resources Management System) applications for claims and expenses. Wrote clean and efficient code as per the requirements.

Projects

Gadget Valley | github.com/mohak92/GadgetValley-MERN | gadget-valley.herokuapp.com

- Technology is continuously evolving gadget valley is an online marketplace to rent the latest tech and try out new products. For example, renting a workstation to finish a project or trying new smartphones every 3 months.
- Led a team 4 developers, implemented API routes in Node.js, components in React and deployed to Heroku.
- Mongo, Express.js, React, and Node.js

Google Books | github.com/mohak92/google-books-mern | boiling-everglades-93367.herokuapp.com

- Find the books you would like to read using google and save them to a database as a list to read them.
- Implemented entire application, performed CRUD operations, called Google API for search results.
- Mongo, Express.js, React and Node.js

Food Finder | github.com/mohak92/FoodFinder | mohak92.github.io/FoodFinder

• A web application to find food near you and recommend food based on weather using Zomato data for restaurant info and Open Weather API for weather data.

- Worked in a team of 5 responsible for dynamically creating info cards and calling the Zomato API for results.
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax

NYT Web Scraper | github.com/mohak92/news-web-scraper | shrouded-forest-52247.herokuapp.com

- Scrape new articles from a website and store in MongoDB, saves article in a separate list to read later, and add notes to news articles.
- Developed entire application implemented server-side logic to scrape and store data into Mongo database.
- Mongo, Express.js, Node.js, Handlebars, CSS3

Education

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, Rutgers University, Somerset NJ (Aug 2019 - Feb 2020) 24-week boot camp dedicated to designing and building applications using Mongo, Express.js, React and Node.js

Full Stack Java Development, Agile and Scrum Bootcamp, Platform by Per Scholas (Oct 2017 - Jan 2018) 12-week boot camp building Java apps, topics covered Java, Spring framework, Design patterns, Agile and Scrum

M.S in Computer Science, New York Institute of Technology, New York NY (Jan 2015 - Dec 2016)
Courses- Analysis of Algorithm, Artificial Intelligence, Operating Systems, Database Design

B.S in Computer Engineering, Rutgers University, New Brunswick NJ

Courses- Data Structures and Algorithm, Object Oriented Programming, Software Engineering, Database Design

Certifications:

Certifications:		
• iOS App Development with Swift Specialization – University of Toronto on Coursera	(Apr 2020)	
 AWS Certified Developer Associate – Amazon Web Services 	(Apr 2019)	
 Certified Blockchain Expert V2 – Blockchain Council 	(Jan 2019)	